This is a fight for our very existence.
The Creator is a science fiction, action, adventure
film directed by Gareth Edwards.
Amid a future war between the human race and the forces of artificial intelligence, a hardened ex-special forces agent grieving the disappearance of his wife, is recruited to
hunt down and kill the Creator, the elusive architect of advanced AI who has developed a mysterious weapon with the power to end the war—and mankind itself.
Joshua, played by John David Washington.
Alphie, played by Madeleine Yuna Voyles.
Maya, played by Gemma Chan.
Colonel Howell, played by Allison Janney.
Harun, played by Ken Watanabe.
Drew, played by Sturgill Simpson.
The Creator is a 2023 American science fiction action film produced and directed
by Gareth Edwards, who co-wrote the screenplay with Chris Weitz.
It stars John David Washington, Gemma Chan, Ken
Watanabe, Sturgill Simpson, and Allison Janney.
Set in 2070, 15 years after artificial intelligence (AI) set off a nuclear detonation in Los Angeles, which started a war of humans against AI, a former
special forces agent is recruited to hunt down and kill the "Creator", who has developed a mysterious weapon with the power to end the war.
Development began in November 2019 when Edwards signed on to direct and write the
project for New Regency and was officially announced in February 2020.
Washington was hired in May 2021, and the rest of
the cast joined over the next year.
Filming began in January 2022 in Thailand with an $80
million production budget, and wrapped that May.
The Creator was released in North America on
September 29, 2023, by 20th Century Studios.
The film grossed $104.3 million worldwide and received
generally positive reviews from critics.
It had two nominations at the 96th Academy Awards, for Best Visual Effects and Best Sound, and was nominated
for Best Science Fiction Film and Best Film Visual / Special Effects at the 51st Saturn Awards.
The film explores themes of artificial intelligence
(a.i.), asia, cyberpunk, robot, space station.
The tone is thought_provoking.